鸡肉
Chicken.
真不错
Good chicken.
是啊  鸡肉诶
Yeah, chicken.
我知道这是鸡肉  我是想知道味道怎么样
I know it's chicken. I want to know what it tastes like.
像鸡肉呗
It tastes like chiken.
-我今天要做手术了  -或许吧  万一收缩了呢
- I'm having surgery today.  - Maybe if the mets have shrunk.
我今天可能要做手术
I am maybe having surgery today,
正因如此  我不能亲自尝试这鸡肉
And as such, I cannost taste the chicken for myself,
我需要你们告诉我到底什么味道的啊
I really need you guys to tell me what it taste like
我得把晚宴确定下来
I  need to nail down this dinner
这样才能在  梅瑞狄斯和德里克的婚礼网站上写告示啊
So I can announce on Meredith and Derek's wedding web site
还有网站啊
There is a web site?
所以请你还是详细的说一下这鸡肉吧
So can you please a little more articulate and just chicken?
-就是这件了  -谢博德医生  你真帅气啊
- That's the one.  - You are very dapper Dr. Shepherd?
真的假的  这可不能开玩笑的啊
You're serious about this. It's not some cool jock.
你看上去超赞  他超赞的  对吧
You look fantastic. He looks fantastic,right?
-是啊  -可不是
- Yeah  - Whatever
记得我们小的时候
Remember when we were little
我们会在操场上  突然咬别的小朋友一口
And we would accidently bite a kid on playplound?
-祝你检查顺利  -鸡肉不错
- Good luck with your scan. - Good codcken.
怎么样
So?
像猪肉
Pork.
我们的老师会边说着抱歉边走开
Our teachers would go, "say you're sorry."
好吧  我来尝尝这鸡肉
Fine. I'll taste the chicken.
我们会说  但词不达意
And we would say it, but we wouldn't mean it.
因为被我们咬的那个孩子  就是活该啊
Because the stupid kid we bit totally deserved it.
不好意思  很抱歉
Oh! oh. sorry. I'm sorry.
小心点
Take care now.
其实...我付不起房租
Hey. so... I can't afford rent.
-欧文对我说"小心点"  -不错啊  三个字呢
- Owen just told me to "take care now."  - Nice. it's three words.
是啊  比她家人对她说的多
Yeah, it's more than she's getting from any of her family.
我老妈沉默  我姑妈沉默
My mom--silent. my aunt--silent.
我妹妹阿丽雅...我知道
My sister Aria-- I know.
我知道我老爸权利有多大
I know how much power my father wields,
但说实话  我又算什么呢
But seriously, I mean, what am i,
对他们甚至我妈来说  我是隐形的  死了的
Invisible, dead to them, to my mother?
你再给他们点时间
Well, you just have to give them some more time.
你们干嘛不直接告诉他们  你俩分手了
I mean, why can't you just tell them you guys broke up?
没人能来管你们跟谁约会的  对吧
It's no one's business who you go out with anyway, right?
我让你单独思考一下
And I will leave you to ponder that.
然而随着我们年长  不断补偿
But as we get older, making amends...
万事不易
Isn't so simple.
你真觉得我该撒谎
You really think I should lie?
我真觉得你该付房租
I really think you should pay rent.
但  不管怎么说  小心点
But, you know, whatever. take care now.
随着操场玩耍的日子结束  就不能再信口开河了
After the playground days are over, you can't just say it.
你得说到做到
You have to mean it.
我送份礼物给你
I got you a present.
我告诉过你了  别给钱我
I told you, you can't give me money,
即便你是个出色的整形科医生
Even if you are a fancy plastic surgeon.
我可不是你的捐赠者  我又不是你情妇
I am not your charity case. I-i am not your mistress.
-我是你朋友  平等的  所以..  -跟钱没关系
- I'm your friend, your equal, so...  - It's not money.
真的吗
Oh, really?
我刚才不过是表演下"贫贱不能移"
'Cause I was just doing the "poor but proud" thing for show
我就快领政府综援了
Before I accepted your government cheese.
这比钞票强多了  等着
It's better than money. Wait.
当然啦  作为一个医生而言  "抱歉"可不是个好词
Of course, when you become a doctor, "sorry" is not a happy word.
那不是意味着"你要死了  我爱莫能助了"
It either means, "you're dying, and I can't help"
她从树上摔下来  把四肢都摔断了
She fell out of a tree and broke all her limbs.
的确更好
Ooh. that is better.
或者意味着"痛苦万分"
Or it means, "this is really gonna hurt."
-多少天  -29天
- How many days?  - 29.
刚治疗完了
Fresh from rehab.
我能给你引见这个区一些好的见面会
I could tell you some good meetings in the area.
谢了  他们把整个名单给我了
Thanks. they--they gave me a whole list.
我们又多了个共同点嘛
So that's one more thing we have in common.
你有没有...跟梅瑞狄斯说过
Have you... talked to Meredith...
莱西呢
To Lexie?
威洛  恐怕你的颧骨也断了
Okay, Willow, I'm afraid your cheekbone looks broken, too.
我得过几周等肿消退些了才能帮你修复
I'll need to wait a few weeks until the swelling goes down to repair that.
几周后  我得去犹他州的一棵树上去
In a few weeks, I'm gonna be up a tree in Utah.
那群畜生公司  用推土机把我从凯里上铲下来
Those corporate bastards, the same ones who just bulldozed me out of Kaili
他们要推平那区域建综合性住宅区
They want to clear-cut acres to build another ski condo complex.
一群杂种!
Sons of bitches!
你说的话我大多没听懂
There is so much about that sentence I do not understand.
你被推土机从哪儿铲下来
Uh, you were bulldozed out of something?
凯丽
Uh, uh, Kaili.
她是颗树  我在上面住了6周
She was the tree that I was living in for the past six weeks.
她是已有200岁的美丽老橡树
She was a beautiful 200-year-old oak
那个树林里到处是200多岁的老橡树
In a Grove full of beautiful 200-year-old oaks.
你给那棵树命名为"凯丽"
You named a tree "Kaili"?
凯丽是夏威夷语  意为"美丽  聪慧"
Kaili is Hawaiian, for "divine beauty and wisdom."
代表了一切美好事物
And she was all of those things.
一切美好事物  而如今却没了
She was all of those things, and now she's gone.
都没了
They're all gone.
就为了雅皮士房子
And for what, yuppie housing?
一群畜生公司
Those corporate bastards!
很抱歉
I'm really sorry,
你在很长一段时间里不能再爬树了
But you're not gonna be climbing up any trees for a good long while.
人怎么住在树上啊
How does one exactly live in a tree?
我的意思是  在树上怎么排除废弃物啊
I mean, how exactly does one say, eliminate waste?
他是...在问  你在哪儿排便
He's, um, asking where your poo goes,
在这个时候问不太合适
Which may not be the most sensitive question
尤其她现在在为她的...
While she's mourning the death of her...
树友们哀悼
Tree friend.
医生  打扰一下
Excuse me, doctor.
很抱歉  年轻帅气的医生
Oh, excuse me, young-and-yummy doctor.
-我能为你效劳吗  -不知道诶  你行吗
- Can I help you?  - I don't know. can you?
你是在找人吗  大妈
Are you looking for someone, ma'am?
天哪  我得假装没听见你刚叫我"大妈"
Oh, gosh. I'm gonna pretend that you didn't just call me "ma'am,"
因为在我脑海里还在呈现咱俩在玩医生游戏
Because I have this image of you and me in my head playing doctor,
然后被你扼杀掉了
And that just kinda ruined it.
好吧  我得回去工作了  祝你好运  一切都是
Okay, I'm gonna go back to work now, but good luck with, whatever.
其实  我在找一名医生
Well, I am looking for a doctor.
神呐  我想现在她该是一名病人了
Gosh, I guess she's a patient now.
伊泽贝尔·斯蒂文斯
Um, Isobel Stevens.
我是...
I'm, uh...
我是她故有
I'm an old friend.
紧随你之后
After you.
医生加绅士  真是倍感帅气
Oh, a doctor and a gentleman. Now that's a double yummy.
-偶滴神呐  谁要结婚了  -天哪  老妈
- My god! who's getting married?!  - Oh, my god. mom.
你怎么会来
What are you doing here?
-老妈  -嘘  保密
- Mom?  - Now shush, cricket.
别让火辣医生觉得我老了
You don't want that hot doctor to think I'm old.
嘿  你也被呼叫了
Hey. You got paged, too?
是啊  说立即到主任办公室
Yeah. Report to the chief's office, stat.
你觉得会是什么事  为什么
What do-- what do you think? why?
-他干嘛那么急呼我们  -我不知道啊
- Why--why would he page us stat?  - I don't know.
我们最近是不是错手杀了人不记得了
Did we kill anyone lately and don't remember?
你们的父亲在这儿
Your father's here.
他禁酒29天  才从康复中心出来
He's 29 days sober, just out of rehab.
他这次很认真  每一阶段都很努力
He's taking it seriously. He's working his steps.
第九个阶段是随时弥补过失
The ninth step is to make amends wherever possible.
这是酗酒康复的关键
It's the key to an alcoholic's recovery
为他的过去犯的过错承担责任
To take responsibility for the wreckage of his past.
我呼你们过来  就是要请你们听他说完
I paged you here to ask you to please hear him out.
就当帮我个忙  听他说完
As a favor to me-- to please hear him out.
-主任  今天我在急诊值班  而且...  -我会处理
- Uh, I'm covering the pit, chief, and--  - I'll cover it.
-但今天有个外伤要来  -我会处理的  梅瑞狄斯
- But there's a trauma coming in.  - I got it, Meredith.
拜托了
Please.
拜托
你在这儿干嘛
Hey, what are you doing here?
主任特别关照我  让我顶替小梅来急诊
The chief specifically asked me to cover Mer in the pit.
我这个月都跟着亨特
I'm on Hunt's service all month.
欧麦利  他们来了  欧麦利  汇报最新消息
O'malley. Hey there now. uh, O'malley, update me.
两辆救护车
Uh, two ambulances.
3位病人  1名伤势严重
Three patients, one critical.
多处枪伤
Multiple gunshot wounds.
麦克·卡尔森  35岁  多处枪伤
Mike Carlson, 35, multiple g.s.w.s.
收缩压88  注射了2剂乳酸林格氏液
Last b.p.--88 systolic after 2 boluses of l.r.
-枪伤位置  -胸口 腹部 背部 腿部 肩部
- Where was he shot?  - Chest, abdomen, back, legs, shoulder.
-这可不是闹着玩的  -我不太清楚
- Someone meant business.  - I'm not so sure about that.
她不是有意的  这是个意外
She didn't mean it. It was an accident.
她不是有意的  她很内疚了
She really didn't mean it. She's sorry.
-麦蒂  告诉他们你很抱歉  -是她开的枪
- Maddy, tell 'em you're sorry.  - She's the shooter?
呼叫主任
Somebody page the chief.
呼吸好多了
Breath sounds are better.
他在胸腹部位中了3抢
He's got three to the thoracoabdominal area.
总共多少伤口
What does that bring the count up to?
这三处  加上腿上七处
These plree,us seven to the legs--
总共十处  不对  两侧还有两处
That's  ten--no,actually,there's two on the side here.
可能打穿身体了  放个棉签看看能否通过
Could be through and through.Put a swab through and see where it goes.
-现在把他反过来吗  -插好尿管先
- Should we roll him now?  - Finish his catheter.
通的过不
Does it enter and exit?
等等  总共11处伤口
Hold on. That makes 11.
还能从伤口看到什么
What can we infer from these injuries?
有血尿  肾应该有问题了
There's blood in the urine,so I'm guessing kidney.
好了  欧麦利  你喊口号  我们把他翻过来
Okay,O'malley,let's roll him on your count.
1  2  3
One,two,three.
背后还有伤口
Oh,yeah. There's more wounds back here.
杨  呼叫  谢博德
Yang,page Shepherd.
先确定他的伤口数  然后把他放稳了
Let's make sure we get an accurate count while we have him positioned.
麦蒂  有什么感觉吗
Maddy,how's this feel?
疼吗
Does it hurt when I do this?
很好  这些伤口呢
Good. Now what about this cut?
能告诉我你脸上的伤是怎么来的吗
Can you tell me how you got this big cut on your face?
她吓坏了
She's scared.
她怕做了坏事之后  你们要把她从我身边带走
She's scared she did a bad thing and you're gonna take her away from me
警察想找你们俩谈谈  曼迪是怎么拿到枪的
The police will want to talk to both of you about how Maddy got the gun.
我们叫了社工  他们很快就到了
We called social services,and they'll be here soon.
他们会全力帮你们回忆这件事的
And they'll give you all the support that you need to come back from this.
没人会把你从妈妈的身边带走
And nobody is gonna take you away from your mom.
好吗  麦蒂  听到我说的了吗
Okay,Maddy? You hear me?
那枪砸到她脸上了  反弹的作用
It hit her in the face-- the gun,the kickback.
-这可不像...  -她就是这么被划到的
- 'Cause this doesn't look like...  - That's how she got the cut.
她爸爸在后院打靶
Her daddy shoots targets in the backyard.
他把枪放下了一会儿
He put the gun down for a minute.
真是笨死了  太愚蠢了
It was stupid. It was really stupid.
她从没想过要伤害他
She never meant to hurt him.
好吧  你待会把这告诉警察  没事的
Okay,you'll tell the police that,and it'll be okay.
不会有事的
Everything will be okay.
我由衷的感到抱歉
I'm so deeply sorry...
我伤害了你们
For every time that I ever hurt you
让你们绝望  失望了那么多次
Or disappointed you or let you down.
我不值得你们原谅
I don't deserve your forgiveness.
但我希望  真心希望  你们给我一个改过自新的机会
But I hope-- I so hope that you'll give me the opportunity to earn it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
恭喜你  你看起来挺好
Congratulations on... you seem well.
祝你好运
Good luck.
还记得114的杰德不
And then you remember Jade from 114? Well...
她去年也查出来有癌症  是乳癌哦
She had a spot of cancer last year. It was breast cancer.
真是遗憾啊  她那俩小山真不错啊
That was such a shame,I thought,'cause she had such a great rack.
天哪  你还记得她那超赞的小山峰不
God,do you remember what a great rack she had?
你以前常这么练习
You used to do all those little exercises like this
就为了能像她那样
To try to get yours to grow like hers.
不管怎么样  我想说  杰德她全割了
Anyway,my point is,Jade,she had 'em cut off-- both of 'em,
不仅保住了小命  还更加楚楚动人了呢
Just to be on the safe side, and they look even better now.
真的哦  她因祸得福  从柠檬变成了哈密瓜了
No,for real. Life gave her lemons and she made cantaloupes.
所以  或许  可能  亲爱的
So maybe,I don't know,maybe,honey,
老妈  听我说  听着  好吗
Um,mom,just,uh,just listen,okay?
我没得乳癌
I... I don'tave breast cancer.
我得了皮肤癌  或者说始于皮肤癌
Okay,I have skin cancer,or what started out as skin cancer--
等等  打住  皮肤癌
Wait,hang on.Skin cancer?
天哪  伊泽贝尔·斯蒂文斯
Oh,god! Isobel Stevens.
你把我吓死了你
Oh,you scared the hell out of me.
你让我一路赶到西雅图
And then you made me come all the way up here to Seattle
就为了那难看的痣啊
Just for some ugly old mole?
-哦  宝贝  -没  我可没有
- Oh,sweetie.  - No,I didn't.
我没叫你过来呀  我都没打过电话给你
I didn't make you come up here. I didn't even call you.
我真的很好奇  是谁打的呢
I'm really--I'm curious. Who did?
谁打的
Who called?
谁打电话叫的她
Who called her?
说真的  谁打的
Seriously,who called her?
你怎么了  怎么哭了
You okay? Are you crying?
-我爸爸来了  -哦
- My dad's here.  - Okay.
他来了  而且他在禁酒
He's here and he's sober,
我很想带你去见他
And I would really like for you to meet him.
今晚吃晚饭怎么样  8点在卡帕罗
How about dinner,tonight? Camparo's at 8:00?
莱西...
Lexie,uh...
老爸们向来不喜欢我
Dads historically do not love me.
从小就是这样
And by that I mean that when I was a-a teenager
老爸们都不喜欢我
Dads did-- did not love me.
之后我还没见过任何人的爸爸呢
And... and that's the last time I had to meet anyone's dad.
我超喜欢你
I'm crazy about you.
我知道我老爸也会的
And--and I know that my dad would be,too.
你别多虑了
You have nothing to worry about.
你让我跟德里克说的时候也这么讲的
That's what you said when you told me to tell Derek.
莱西  我跟你爸爸的年龄差比跟你的要小
Lexie,I'm closer to your dad's age than yours.
我觉得  他或许不会那么的喜欢我
So I'm thinking he-- he may not... love me so much.
我们现在不是很好嘛
You know,what we have is fantastic.
为什么我们不能保持两人世界呢
Why don't we just... keep it for us?
不好意思  我在找我的妹妹凯琳·泽尔蒙
Excuse me. I'm looking for my sister--Karen Zelmann.
我们有个威洛·泽尔蒙在里面
Well,I have a Willow Zelmann in--in there.
-她叫凯琳  -我叫威洛
- Her name is Karen.  - My name is Willow!
我跟你说过了
I told you.
我告诉你会发生这样的事
I told you this would happen.
我叫你从那颗该死的树上下来  凯琳
I told you to come down out of the damn tree,Karen.
进行的如何啊
Uh,how'd it go?
格蕾医生  你有空的话  帮曼迪清洗缝合下伤口
Dr.Grey,if you're free,Maddy here could use a little cleaning and laceration repair
我被呼叫了
'Cause I'm being paged.
好的
Absolutely.
梅瑞狄斯
Meredith.
-你没事吧  -我很好啊
- Are you okay?  - I'm great.
谢啦
Thanks.
嘿  麦蒂  我是格蕾医生
Hey,Maddy. I'm Dr. Grey.
介意我看下你脸上的伤口吗
You mind if I take a look at that cut on your face?
她真的很抱歉  非常抱歉
You know,she's so sorry. She's so sorry.
我爸爸会死吗
Is my daddy gonna die?
我不知道  但愿不会吧
I don't know. I hope not.
还有5颗子弹在体内
Five bullets still inside.
总共被射了多少枪
How many gunshots total?
总共有25处伤口  还有5颗留在体内
There are 25 wounds total. 5 are lodged inside.
2处擦伤  9处穿透  一共挨了17枪
Two graze wounds,nine through and throughs so 17 bullets.
17枪
17?
我以为是意外枪伤啊
I thought this was an accidental shooting.
怎么会呢
How come?
什么怎么会呢
How come what?
他怎么会不死呢  我对他开了好多枪呢啊
How come he don't die? I shot him lots of times.
他怎么会还不死
How come he don't die?
她还只是个小姑娘  是个孩子
She's just a little girl,a baby.
她不是要杀死他  她只是...
She wasn't really trying to kill him. She was...
她压根什么都不懂
She doesn't even understand what that means.
她只是想阻止他  只是为了阻止他
She was just trying to stop him. She was only trying to stop him.
她脸上的伤也不是来自枪把
So that cut on her face didn't come from the gun?
那是他打的
He was hitting her.
他爱我们的
He loves us.
爸爸还是爱我们的  麦蒂  他只是偶尔会发发疯
Daddy loves us,Maddy. And sometimes he just gets mad.
他已经很克制了
And he's been working on it.
他已经很努力了
He's been working on it so hard.
而她只是为了阻止他
But she was just trying to stop him.
她不是要杀他
She wasn't trying to kill him.
请谅解
Please understanded
她不过是个孩子
She was just a  little girl.
真的吗
Oh, really?
真的
Uh-huh. really?
那太好了  太好了
Oh, yeah, that's great. That's great.
谢谢  谢谢你  亲亲
Oh, thank you. Yes, thank you, hon.
感激不尽
Thanks a million. oh.
好消息  蟋蟀
Oh, that's great news, Cricket.
你会好起来的
You're gonna be just fine.
真的
Oh, yeah?
我猜猜  你的灵媒告诉你的
Let me guess. Your psychic told you that?
他不仅仅是个老灵媒
It's not just any old psychic.
他是我所见过的最好的
He's the best that i've ever heard of.
反正  他说这个皮肤癌
Anyway, he said that skin cancer
只要及时发现是可以治好的
Is highly curable if caught early.
太好了
Oh, that's so great.
会上网的灵媒
A psychic with internet access.
让我猜猜这电话花了你多少钱  妈妈
Let me guess how much that call cost you, mother.
19.99美元一分钟吗
$19.99 a minute?
蟋蟀  当你的孩子生病时
Well, when you have a sick child, Cricket,
你就不在意钱了
Money's not really the first thing on your mind.
你看上去很能干  贝利医生
You seem like a very capable doctor, Dr. Bailey.
我能认为你及时发现了我女儿的皮肤癌吗
Can I trust that you caught my daughter's skin cancer early?
这个么  史蒂文斯夫人
Um... well, uh, Mrs. Stevens--
别  叫我罗比  亲亲
Oh, no. call me Robbie, hon.
妈妈  别叫她亲亲
No, mom. don't call her hon.
别管贝利叫亲亲
Don't call bailey hon.
如果有什么问题就问我
You know, if you have questions you can just ask me.
她很忙   而我的病
She's very busy, and this thing i have,
有点复杂  所以
It's complicated, so...
我知道有点复杂  伊泽贝尔  我不是白痴
I know it's complicated, Isobel I'm not a complete idiot.
我在泰拉[全美超模评委]的节目上见过
Now i saw this thing on tyra's show.
有个女的在私处有颗痣
There was this woman who had a mole on her private parts.
皮肤科医生不厌其烦帮她检查
And the dermatologist did not bother to check her privates
虽然她以为会是妇科医生  可能妇科医生
'cause she thought that the gynie woulda done it. Maybe the gynie
没检查  可能她连妇科都没进  我不知道
Didn't do it. Maybe she didn't even go to the gynie. i don't know.
反正  情况很严重  她秃头了  惨不忍睹
Anyway, it was bad. She was bald and everything.
她的痣不是在私处  是吗
She did not have a mole on her private parts, did she?
不是  夫人  她不是
No, ma'am. No, she did not.
太好了
Good.
他得马上做手术  子弹射进腹部
We need to take him in now. g.s.w.s to the abdomen,
有血尿  要害部位不稳定
Hematuria, vitals signs are unstable.
夫人  他几乎有所有内脏问题
Ma'am, he has major internal injuries.
我们得马上把他推进手术室
We're rushing him to surgery now.
等等
Wait!
他进去前麦蒂要向他道歉
Maddy needs to tell her daddy she's sorry before he goes.
孩子  告诉爸爸你很抱歉
Baby, you need to tell your daddy you're sorry.
麦蒂  开刀可能会有生命危险
Maddy, people die in surgery.
你不想还没道歉
You don't want your daddy to die
爸爸就去世了吧
Without telling him how sorry you are.
来  我们去告诉他我们爱他
Come on. let's go tell him we love him.
-别去  别  -你说什么
- You know, no.  - No. what?
-麦蒂  留在这  -格蕾医生
- Maddy, stay right here, okay?  - Dr. Grey--
不  她不能去向他道歉
No, she will not go apologize to him.
你该向她道歉
You should be apologizing to her.
我知道你也是受害者
I understand you're a victim here,
但当你女儿有危险时
There is no room for you to be a victim
你不能只做受害者
When your 6 year old is on the line.
她比你坚强  你六岁的孩子
She's stronger than you. Your 6 year old
至少做了点事  她比你坚强
is stronger than you at least she did something.
她为了你们俩挺身而出
she stood up for the two of you,
而你却没做到
Which is more than you did for her.
不行  她不能向他道歉
No, she won't apologize to him.
非常感谢  我会给你回电的
Thank you so much. All right. I'll call you back.
我有好消息  我有个朋友
Listen, I have great news. I have an associate
认识切斯特和沃纳
Who has a contact at schuster and werner.
邋遢鬼和重罪犯
More like dirtbag and felon.
他们答应付医疗费
they've agreed to pay the medical bills
而且不指控你非法侵入
And to not sue you for trespassing
只要你签份声明不会控告他们
If you sign a contract saying you won't sue them
并且不会再侵犯他们的财产
And you won't trespass on any of their propert ever again
你知道多少英亩的森林
Do you know how many acres of forest
被他们轻而易举地毁了
They have single-handedly destroyed,
多少生态系统再也无法复原吗
How many ecosystems will never be restored?
蜜蜂在死去  朱丽
The bees are dying, Julie.
-气温持续升高  -打扰一下
- The temperature is rising.  - I'm sorry.
我能单独和我妹妹聊会吗
Is it possible i could have a moment alone with my sister?
你得签这协议  凯伦
You will sign this deal, Karen.
我叫薇乐
My name is willow!
真庆幸我没有姐妹
I can't say i'm sorry i never had siblings.
-她们吵架是因为她们在乎对方  -这样吗
- They're yelling 'cause they care. - That how it works?
是这样的  对某些家庭来说
Yeah, it is. in some families, it is.
我希望她们争吵
I expected them to yell, you know?
不要沉默
I didn't expect silence.
为什么不打电话叫人来治精神失常
Why don't you call 'em and claim temporary insanity?
你不一定要和辣妹结束的
You don't have to end it with roller girl.
-只要你认错  -杨也是这么说的
- Just say you did.  - Yang said the same thing.
那是因为这与他们无关
That's because it's none of their business.
你不该这样被伤心的
There's no reason you should have to hurt this much.
我知道你
I can see that you're...
生我的气
Angry with me.
-也许生你母亲的气  但是  -别这样
- And maybe angry with your mother, but--  - Don't do that.
我不是你的朋友 也不是你的家人
I'm not your friend and i am not your family.
你不能因私人原因把我叫进你办公室
You don't get to call me into your office on personal business,
而且现在你不能像这样对我说话
And you don't get to speak to me this way right now.
这是滥用职权
It's an abuse of power.
我是住院医生  我是你手下
I'm a resident. I work for you.
你必须像对个住院医生一样跟我说话
You have to speak to me like i'm a resident.
至于刚才那事  主任
And for the record, chief,
得有人为那小女孩说话
Somebody had to stand up for that little girl,
我不会道歉的
And i make no apologies for that.
你想只做个住院医生  行
You want to just be a resident? Fine.
没问题
All right, then.
那女士是家庭暴力的受害者
That woman is a victim of domestic violence.
这医院应该是她来治疗
This hospital is supposed to be a safe place
和倾诉的庇护所
For her to come and tell her story.
作为医生我们应该帮助她
And as her doctors, it is our job to help her.
你没有尽到你的责任
You did not do your job.
相反  你伤害了一个已受伤的女人
Instead, you further battered a battered woman.
-那那小女孩怎么办  -格蕾医生
- What about that little girl?  - Dr. Grey,
你不许再管那孩子
you will stay away from that child.
你不许再管这家人
You will stay away from that family.
不许离他们100英尺以内
You will not come within 100 feet of them.
如果你做不到  你将被停职
And if you do, you will be suspended from this hospital
重新评估你作为住院医生的
Pending re-evaluation of your
情绪和心理健康状况
emotional and mental fitness for residency.
下腔静脉和主动脉有刮痕
The i.v.c. and the aorta are nicked.
欧麦利  拿几个夹子来
O'malley, get in there with some clips.
我要把血管夹住
I'm gonna need the angular vascular clamp.
没用  他还在失血
Nothing's stopping. He's still bleeding out.
杨  别动
Don't move, Yang.
我要吸一下那里
I need some more suction in there.
我知道你和理查德·韦伯是朋友
I know richard webber is your friend.
跟理查德无关
this is not about Richard
有关  跟他有关
It is. It is about him.
因为工作原因
Because I have to deal with him
我每天都要和他接触
On a professional basis every day,
我试着划清界限  但他无动于衷
And i have tried to draw a line, and he won't respect it.
他无动于衷
He doesn't respect it
而且他还利用和你的关系
And he uses his relationship with you--
理查德没有利用
richard doesn't uses
别帮他说话  站我这边
Stop defending him. Be on my side.
-我需要你站在我这边  -好吧
- I need you to be on my side.  - Okay.
他不是你的挚友  他不是你的克里斯蒂娜
He's not your best friend. He's not your cristina.
所以我觉得可以跟你说
Which is why i feel like it's okay to say to you
他不能参加我们的婚礼
He is not invited to our wedding.
因为我发誓  德里克  他在我就不去了
Because i swear, Derek, if he is there, i won't be.
而我是新娘  我必须去
And i'm the bride, so i have to be.
-所以我求求你  他不去好吗  -好
- So i'm begging you, please. He's not invited, okay?  - Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you. mm-hmm.
如果你不签协议  谁来付医疗费
If you don't make this deal, who's gonna pay your bills,
-谁来照顾你  -他们想杀了我
- Who's gonna take care of you?  - They tried to kill me,
就像他们杀凯莉
just like they killed Kaili,
杀所有那些无力抵抗的树一样
Just like they killed all of those defenseless trees,
所有那些无力抵抗的树上生物
All of the defenseless creatures that live in those trees.
你不是无力抵抗的树上生物  凯伦
You are not a defenseless, tree-living creature, Karen.
你是个成年女人
You are an adult woman
并且执着地决定要非法入侵
Who made a conscious decision to trespass.
这是难以置信地愚蠢  难以置信地幼稚
It was unbelievably stupid, unbelievably naive--
难以置信地不负责任
Just unbelievably irresponsible.
也是难以置信地勇敢
What about the part that it is unbelievably brave
-什么  -树与我无关
- Excuse me?  - Trees may not be my thing,
但是尽管我认为这很傻  她确实很勇敢
But even if i thought it was stupid, it was still brave.
她住在一棵200岁的树上
I mean, she slept in a 200-year-old tree
看着一个推土机把她推下来
And watched as a bulldozer knocked her off of it
只是因为她要维护自己的信仰
Because she was standing up for what she believed in.
你得承认  她真他妈难以置信地勇敢
You have to admit, she's unbelievably freakin' brave.
怎么能说树与你无关
how can trees not be your thing
凯伦  凯伦
Karen? karen?
糟糕  脉象很弱  我们从0-2开始
Damn it. Her pulse is weak. Let's start her on 0-2.
看看腿上有没有脉搏
See if you can get a femoral pulse.
大腿在流血
Okay, she's bleeding out from her femur.
我们得让她稳下来
We need to get her stabilized.
怎么回事  我妹妹怎么了
What's going on? What's happening with my sister
朱丽  保持冷静
Julie, you need to clear out.
告诉我我妹妹怎么了
Tell me what's happening with my sister
-带她出去 -告诉我怎么回事
- Get her out of here, please.  - Tell me what's happening.
注入乳酸林格氏 并注射浓缩红细胞
Put the l.r. on a rapid transfuser and hang p-rbcs.
准备转移  通知手术室我们马上就到
Get ready for transport, tell the o.r. we're on our way now!
该死  该死  太多流血部位
Damn it! Damn it! There's too many bleeders.
再来一袋O型血  拿点血纤蛋白粘合剂来
Hang another bag of o-neg and get me some fibrin sealant.
-我能帮忙吗  -你在帮忙
- Can i help?  - You are helping.
流血的部位比你的人手还多
You've got more bleeders than you have hands.
抱歉
Sorry.
不不  你来  你  过去换下杨
No, no, that's it. you, get in here and take over for yang.
-杨  跑去我的车子  -什么
- Yang, run to my truck.  - What?
去我的车子那  我总停车那地方
Run to my truck. it's where i always park it.
快点  杂物箱里有个绿包
Run fast. in the glovebox, there's a green bag.
用力拉牵引器  会吗
Pull harder on that retractor, would you?
-进去后  -我是外科医生  为什么
- Really get in--  - I'm a surgeon why
我在救人命  杨  快
I'm trying to save a life here, Yang. run!
是情人之卡
Ooh, the lovers card.
知道什么意思吗
Do you know what this means?
知道  不知道  知道
Yes. no. yes.
我  妈妈  你能不能消停会儿  行吗
I'm--mom, can you please just shut up? okay?
这是肉  肯定是某种肉
It's meat. definitely some kind of meat.
你快逼死我了  明白吗
You're killing me, you know that?
意味着性生活很棒
It means that the sex is hot. hmm?
我赌那个小痣
Now i bet that little old mole
没影响到你们  对吗
doesn't get in the way there am i right?
亲爱的  听着
Honey, hey, listen,
我的拍片时间到了吗
Isn't it time for my scan?
现在是不是拍片时间了
Isn't it time for my scan right now?
我去看看是不是该开始了
I'll--i'll go check, see if i can get things moving on
谢谢你
Thank you
跟我说说棒医生
So tell me about dr. Hottie.
你们在一起多久了
How long have you all been together?
妈
Mom...
那不仅仅是颗痣
It's not just a mole.
我得的是四级黑素瘤
I have stage iv melanoma.
在我身体里  不仅仅是颗痣
It's in my organs. it's not just a mole.
你身体里可没有皮肤  亲亲
Now you don't have skin on your organs, hon.
这说不通啊
That doesn't make a whole lot of sense.
别总对我叹气  伊泽贝尔
Don't just sigh at me, isobel.
解释清楚
Just, you know, just explain.
好吧
Okay. um...
你记得格莱米在甲状腺上长过肿瘤
You remember when-- when grammy had that tumor on her thyroid?
格莱米死了
Grammy died.
她死了  她
She died. She...
没过多久  就死了
Really soon after that, she died.
你  你告诉  你告诉我的是
Wh-- What are you t-- telling me...
你长了颗痣
You have a mole.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你  你只是  长了颗痣
You--you just-- you have a mole.
我很抱歉  抱歉  那
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. wh--
那是个很差劲的比喻
That was a really bad comparison.
-我得的和格莱米完全不一样  -不会的  不会的
- What i have is nothing like what Grammy has.  - No. No.
好了  我很抱歉  我很抱歉
Okay, i'm sorry. i'm sorry.
深呼吸  没事的  没事
Just breathe. it's okay. i'm okay.
深呼吸好吗  没事的
Just breathe, okay? it's okay.
没事  没事
It's okay. i'm okay.
深呼吸
Just breathe.
我有种强烈的预感
Now i've got a good feeling about this.
我觉得那些甲硫氨酸已经完全萎缩
I think those mets are shrunk way down,
然后任我轻松杀进去把剩下的取出来
And i think i'm gonna go right in and take the rest out.
真的  你这么认为吗
Really? You think that?
你的灵媒这么说的吗
Did your psychic tell you so?
这片子一定会是好的  一定得是好的
This scan has to be good. It has to be good.
放松  听着  只要这不是  不是世界末日
Take easy. L-listen, if it's not, it's not the end of the world.
总有别的治疗方法
There are other therapies that we can try--
她不会走的  如果结果不好
She won't leave. If this scan isn't good,
如果我不告诉她好消息  她不会走的
If i can't give her good news, she won't leave.
我爱我妈妈  我不想听着忘恩负义  只是
I love my mom. I don't mean to sound ungrateful. It just...
是我  我打给她的
it was me. I called her.
我以为  我以为是阿历克斯或乔治
I really... I really thought it was Alex or George--
我打了因为
It was me because...
听着  如果我孩子病了  我会想知道
Look, i would want to know if my kid was sick,
而如果我病了  我想我妈知道
And if i was sick, i would want my mom.
我以为是你太高傲
I just thought that you were being too proud
或是你想保护她
Or that you were just trying to protect her,
但我现在明白了  你只是在保护自己
But now i get that you were just trying to protect yourself.
她不是坏人  她是个好母亲
She's not a bad person. She was a great mom.
她只是  有些孤陋寡闻  孤陋寡闻
She's just... limited. She's... limited.
这片子一定得好
The scan has to be good.
一定得好
It has to be good.
-再来点血  -马上  -加油  薇乐
- Hang more blood.  - Right away.  - Come on, willow.
加油  你住在树上
Come on, you lived in a tree.
你拉在桶里  看在上帝的份上
You crapped in a bucket, for god sake.
-你能办到  -她拉在桶里吗
- You can do this.  - She crapped in a bucket?
-你在这干嘛  -在上面看
- What are you doing here?  - Saw it on the board.
我从没见过插进大腿的髓内杆
I've never seen an intramedullary rod put into a femur.
-桶里  -对  滑车上的桶
- So... bucket.  - Yeah. A bucket on a pulley.
她不是在树上么
She's, uh, up in a tree right
所以她每天把粪桶放下来给她朋友
So she lowers a crap bucket to her friend every day,
倒掉  洗好  再放上食物
Who empties it, cleans it, puts food in it
然后放上去给她
And then sends it back up the tree.
感人的友情
Oh, that's friendship.
没错
Yeah.
医学院教我们
You know, they teach us in med school
不要太关心病人
How not to care so much.
我们把病人盖起来这样就看不到他们的脸
We drape the patients so we don't see their faces.
我们尝试一切方法去减少关心
We do a thousand different things to care a little less.
但你几乎疯狂地关心着  我喜欢
But you care like crazy, and i love that.
我会一直喜欢
And i'll keep loving that,
哪怕你决定向家人撒谎
Even if you decide to lie to your family.
杨  干得好
Nice work, yang.
打开包  看到蓝色标签的瓶子了吗
Open the bag. See the bottle with the blue label?
打开倒进无菌瓶里
Open it and pour it into a sterile basin
然后给欧麦利
And give it to o'malley.
对  摇晃着倒在失血部位
Okay, shake it onto the wound right over the bleeders,
-多点  -这是什么
- A lot of it.  - What is this stuff?
我们在野外常用这个
Uh, uh, we used it in the field all the time.
这不受药品管理局认可  但它救了很多人
It's not f.d.a. approved, but it's saved a lot of lives.
当你没有时间封合
When, uh, you don't have time to stitch a guy up,
倒一些这个上去能止血
You pour some of this on, and it just holds things
直到能做手术为止
Until you get him to an o.r.
你看  它把整个伤口堵住了
oh, look at that.It's locking up the entire wound. it
让身体恢复
replicates the body'
这不是根本的治疗方法  它只能为我们争取时间
It's not a permanent solution, but it buys us some time.
血压在上升  情况稳定了
B.p. is going up. he's stabilizing.
好神奇啊
Magical.
我有感觉你会好起来的
I think it's gonna be fine.
我觉得那些肿块会变得非常小
I think those mets are gonna be just teeny tiny.
是转移灶  妈妈
It's, uh, mets, mom. mets.
大都会  打棒球的大都会队吗
Mets? like baseball?
是的  大都会队
Yeah, like baseball.
好了  好消息  非常好的消息
Okay, uh, good news. great news.
几乎没有癌细胞了
The cancer's practically gone.
看来你的直觉蛮准的  斯蒂文斯太太
It looks like your psychic was right, mrs. stevens.
毕竟我们治疗及时
Looks like we caught it early after all.
谢谢  感谢上帝
Oh, thank you, god! thank you.
我的宝贝啊
Oh, my baby.
耶和华  玛利亚  约瑟夫
Jesus, mary and joseph,
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
还有谢谢你
Oh, thank you! oh.
谢谢  实在太感谢了
Thank you! thank you! thank you! thank you.
我就知道你会好的
But i knew it.
对吧
Didn't i?
我就知道
I knew it.
因为你是我的蟋蟀
I knew because you're my cricket.
你不会有事的
Nothing can happen to you.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, mom.
我也爱你  我的小女孩
Oh, i love you, too, my baby girl.
我很爱很爱你
I love you so, so much.
天啊  你看我  又脏又乱的
God, look at me. i must be a mess.
我要去整理一下  好吗
Well, i'm gonna go clean up, okay?
然后呢  然后我要给杰德
And then, uh, and then i'm gonna call jade...
和诺里斯太太报个好消息
And mrs. norris, too.
他们都被我弄得担心死了
I got them all so worried. oh.
告诉我吧
Just tell me.
转移灶是萎缩了一些
The mets have shrunk some,
但是有新的出现
But there are new mets, too--
在小肠里发现几个新的转移灶
Several new mets in the small bowel.
不能手术切除咯
No surgery, then.
我打算做手术
Oh, i'm gonna operate.
我会尽我所能把它们都切除
I'm going to take out absolutely everything i can,
我会竭尽全力的
Be as aggressive as i can,
把他们都拿出来  好吗
And then we'll take it from there. okay.
很好
Okay.
你应该吸取教训
You just have to give her some room.
给她留点空间
You two have history。
我道歉了
i apologized.
我知道  但是她已经受不了了
I know, and it's loaded.
他一直在对我尖叫说我不是她父亲
she keeps yelling at me that i am not her father
是的  我不是
Well, i'm not.
我只是爱上了她的母亲
I fell in love with her mother. that's all i did.
她妈妈一直都没有忘记过你
Her mother never got over you.
她也没有打算
And she's not gonna
好了  这是我的错
well, that's not my fault.
人谁无过啊  况且我当时还年轻
Look, i was young. lots of people have affairs.
他们会有做错事  但是他们不会
They have affairs, and they don't--
你看  我离开艾利之后她做的事情
Look, what ellis did after i left?
那该算在她头上
That's on ellis.
我只是在努力经营医院
And i'm trying to run a hospital here.
她已经尽力了  理查
She's doing the best she can, richard.
显然她尽的力还不够  如果其他住院医生
Well, her best isn't good enough. if any other resident--
如果有住院医生像她今天这样糟的话
If any other resident pulled the crap she did today...
我是因为看在你的面子上才没有炒她
She is still here because of my history with you.
这就是唯一的原因
That's it. that's the only reason.
你一直在说你不是她的父亲  但是
You keep saying you're not her father, but--
好了  你知道吗  我们说了这么久
Okay, you know what? since we're talking,
你是我认识的人中最专业的最冷静的人
You're the most professional guy i know, most levelheaded,
但你一谈到梅瑞狄斯·格蕾就完全失去理智
Except when it comes to meredith grey.
你给我的感觉糟透了
You gave me hell.
你知道  你不再是院长的样子
You know, you weren't gonna give me chief
因为我跟梅瑞狄斯·格蕾一起
Because i was dating meredith grey.
你就告诉她戒指的事情
You told her about the ring.
你让她到树林去带我回来
You sent her out to the woods to bring me back.
这不是在经营医院
That's not running a hospital.
你叫她到你办公室去试礼服
You paged her to your office to try on dresses.
你今天又让她去烦撒切尔的事
You paged her again today for thatcher.
你跟她的关系太复杂了
You have history with her.
你一直都在说你不是他的父亲
You keep saying that you're not her father.
但你所做的  表明你关心她的家庭
But the way you act? you consider her family.
不管值得与否
For what it's worth...
怎么了
What happened?
亨特太神了
hunt is incredible.
那人本该救不活的  17颗子弹啊
The guy shouldn't be alive. 17 bullets.
他现在只有一个肺和一个肾
He has one lung. he's got one kidney left.
-格蕾医生  -梅瑞狄斯
Dr. grey. meredith.
我为我之前说过的话跟你道歉
I'm sorry for the way i spoke to you earlier.
-格蕾医生  -梅瑞狄斯  不要
Dr. grey. meredith, don't.
我知道我越界了  我也知道
I know i was out of line, and i know
我不能想象你们经历了什么
I can't possib imagine what you've been through.
但我知道关于你女儿的故事不应该是这样的
But i also know that this cannot be your daughter's story--
她为了保护妈妈而射击了爸爸17枪
That she shot her dad 17 times to protect her mom,
而你却选择跟他一起
And you went back to him.
你应该在你们两个还能改变的时候
You have to change her story
改变她的故事  改写她的人生
While you still have a chance, for both of you.
为了她  为了你的小女孩
But for her, but for your little girl...
你应该要改写她的人生
You have to change her story.
我会收拾一下离开的
I'll pack my stuff.
她失血过多  但是她的情况稳定下来了
She lost a lot of blood, but she's stable now.
他们该知道的
They weighed the cost.
什么
I'm sorry?
他们宁愿把她杀了
They weighed the cost of killing her
也不肯让她住在树上
Over letting her stay up there.
后来他们就用推土机
And then they got a bulldozer
把树推到让她下来
And they knocked her out of a tree.
他们把我的宝贝妹妹从树上推下来
They knocked my baby sister out of a tree.
朱尔斯
Jules.
我在这呢
I'm here.
Hey, i'm here.
我起诉了切斯特和沃纳
I filed a lawsuit against schuster and werner--
要求赔偿1000万元
A $10-million lawsuit.
我们要那些混蛋付出代价
We're gonna make those bastards pay for this.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
我要他们付出代价
I'm gonna make them pay.
我们就能用这1000万种好多好多的树了
We could plant so many trees with $10 million.
当我们胜诉的时候
And when we win,
支票的抬头就会写着  凯伦
The check will be made out to "karen."
树女熬过了
Our tree girl made it through?
我不会撒谎  但即使他们认为我错了
I can't lie, even if they think i'm wrong,
即使他们不懂
Even if they don't understand,
即使他们认为我是疯子
Even if they think i'm crazy.
我还是我
I'm me.
他们应该接受我
They're supposed to accept me.
他们应该支持我
They're supposed to support me.
他们应该要爱护我  你明白吗
They're supposed to love me, you know?
我不会撒谎的
I can't lie.
好吧
Oh, great.
又一次的真心对话吗
Is this another heart-to-heart?
我知道你不喜欢我
I know you don't like me.
而且你有权利不喜欢我
And you have every right not to like me.
我是滥用权力  但现在我站在你面前
I have abused my power, but now i'm here on your turf,
我要说的是
And what i need to say...
What i need to say is...
我有在注意你妈妈所做的一切
I saw what your mother was doing.
我知道你是怎么被忽视的
I saw how neglected you were,
我知道她是怎样抛弃你父亲的
I saw her drive your father off,
我也为此而深感内疚
And i spent a lot of time beating myself up about that.
但这些对你来说有什么好处呢
But what does that do for you?
没有  一点都没有
nothing. nothing.
我不是你的支持者
I wasn't your advocate.
我不是你的勇士
I didn't fight for you.
我也没有给你坚强的后盾
I never stood up for you.
我逃避责任
I let myself off the hook.
我用年轻做借口来为自己逃避责任
I told myself i was young and didn't know any better,
但我是应该负责任的
But i did know better.
我当时并没有比你现在年轻多少
I wasn't much younger than you are now.
我本该为你抗争的  梅瑞狄斯
I should've fought for you, meredith...
就像你今天为那小女孩做的一样
Like you fought for that child today.
我告诉自己我不是你的父亲
I told myself that i wasn't your father,
那不是我的责任
That it wasn't my responsibility,
我不该插手你的事情
That i was right not to butt in.
我让我自己逃避责任
I let myself off the hook.
你当时绝望了
You were helpless.
你当时  只是个小孩
You were... you were a baby...
一个漂亮的
A beautiful...
聪明的可爱的小女孩
Smart, funny little girl...
但是没有人来保护你
And no one stood up for you.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
作为一个医生  我们不能释怀我们的错误
As doctors, we can't undo our mistakes,
我们不能因为错误而原谅自己
And we rarely forgive ourselves for them,
但是这是我们的职业造成的
But it's a hazard of the trade.
但是作为人类一份子
But as human beings,
我们一直都想做得好一点  再好一点
We can always try to do better, to be better,
甚至明知不可能但还是想纠正错误
To right a wrong even when it feels irreversible.
你确定你不需要我在这
Are you sure you don't want me to stay?
我确定
I'm sure.
我很好
I'm okay.
我会很好的
I'll be okay.
那  当你不舒服的时候  记得找我
Well... if you're not, you know where to find me.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, mom.
我很爱你
I love you so much.
但是我们最好
But we do better
把爱的距离拉远一点
Lovin' each other from a distance.
让你住停车场实在是太委屈了
You were always too good for that trailer park...
我就知道
That i knew.
我或许不是很了解
I might owt kn that much,
我或许不如你聪明  但是
And i might not be quite as smart as you, but...
我就知道
I always knew that.
当然  对不起  不能补偿你什么
Of course "i'm sorry" doesn't always cut it.
或许是因为我们把这话用烂了
Maybe because we use it so many different ways--
把它作为武器  作为借口
As a weapon, as an excuse.
今天表现很好哦
Nice work today.
今天表现很好哦  别开玩笑了
"nice work today"? seriously?
什么
I'm sorry?
跑去我的货车那
"run to my truck."
你让欧麦利止血
You've got o'malley clipping bleeders,
却让我跑去你的货车那
And you're telling me to run to your truck.
是因为你知道我的货车长什么样子  但欧麦利不知道啊
You know what my truck looks like. o'malley doesn't.
你的那趟小跑救了
And that--that run you took? it saved
-那个人的性命啊  -你整天
-a guy's life.  -You all day
今天你整天就教欧麦利  把我晾在一边
All day you were teaching o'malley and you ignored me.
欧麦利想选外科
o'malley wants to
但你早就选了心脏科了
You've already declared cardio.
我今天没做错任何事
I didn't do anything wrong today.
我跟对待其他人一样的对待你
I treated you like i would anyone else.
我跟其他人不同
No, not like anyone else.
你要保重  什么意思
"take care now"?! what is that?!
干嘛  你现在开心了吧
What, are you, like, you know, happy now?
你算什么啊你
What--what are you?
玩过就算了吗
You know, just a "choke 'em and forget 'em" kinda guy?
你好啊  自己保重
"hey there now. take care now.
做的很好  杨  这算什么
Nice work, yang." what is this?
是我的心理医生  我心理医生给我的这些句子
It's my shrink. my shrink gave me these sentences--
我们  我们一起想的句子
We--we, uh, we came up with them together.
全是3个字组成的句子
They're all 3-word sentences
我才能跟你讲话
So i'd have things to say to you
取代那三个字
Instead of the three words that are...
这快把我给弄疯了
That are killing me...
你知道我想说的三个字是什么
The three words that you know i feel
但我讲不出来
But i can't say them,
因为我一旦讲出来了
Because it would be cruel to say them
对你来说将是很残忍的
Because i am no good for you.
我不想你去折磨你自己
I don't want to torture you.
我知道我不能跟你在一起
I don't want to look at you longingly
所以我不能对你有做渴望
When i know i can't be with you.
是的  我是在笑
So, yeah, i'm smiling
我是在说  自己保重哦
And i'm saying "take care now."
我在让你逃离我
I'm letting you off the hook.
我在尝试
I'm trying.
我在努力尝试放开你
I'm trying so hard to let you off the hook.
我在尝试让我所你对
I'm trying to make it right,
做的一起恢复正常
What i did to you.
你明白吗
Can't you see that?
我只是想让一切恢复正常
I'm just trying to make it right.
自己保重
Take care now.
当我们真的感到抱歉的时候
But when we are really sorry,
当我们把它正确应用时
When we use it right,
真实表达我们的意思时
When we mean it...
我们还是分开比较好
We're leaving... for good.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
我知道
And as i understand it,
你现在太虚弱  我想短期内你都不会找到我们的
You'll be too weak to follow us anytime soon,
我确信你以后都不会找到我们的
So i'm pretty sure you won't be able to follow us later.
所以  我们是来告别的
So... we're here to say good-bye.
麦蒂  跟爸爸说再见
Maddy, say good-bye to daddy.
这是你最后一次见他了
This is the last you'll be eing of him.
爸爸再见  保重身体
Bye, daddy. feel better.
格蕾医生  再见
Bye, dr. grey.
麦蒂再见
Bye, maddy.
当我们用行动来弥补语言的不足时
When our actions say what words never can...
抱歉  我来晚了
Sorry i'm late.
爸爸
Uh... d-dad,
这是  马克·斯隆
This is, um, mark sloan.
马克·斯隆医生  他是我的老师
Dr. mark sloan. he--he's my, uh-- teacher?
不 不
No, no.
他是我的
He--he's my...
他是  马克
He's... mark.
很高兴见到你  格雷先生
Nice to meet you, mr. grey.
真高兴见到你
It's so nice to meet you.
请坐吧
Please, grab a chair.
好的  这味道有点像虾子
Okay, that tastes like shrimp.
阿历克斯
Alex...
听着  但这虾子的味道有点
Okay, but listen, the shrimp kinda tastes...
甜甜辣辣的
Sweet and spicy,
你知道吗  就想我们的第一次约会
You know, kinda like our first date--
甜的部分呢
The good part,
幸好我没有在走廊里亲你
The part before i didn't kiss you on the front porch.
很好  不错
Okay, nice.
那鸡肉就像是
And the chicken tastes like a drive to the beach
把车窗都开着开车去海边的感觉
With the windows down
狗把头伸到车窗外
And the dog hanging out the window,
就像你还是小朋友的时候  咸咸的
Like when you were a kid, like, salty.
味道很好  但是如果要选的话
It tastes good, but i'd definitely go for the shrimp
我会选择虾子
If we have to choose.
还有一个
there's one more.
好了  这吃起来像粪便
Okay, yeah. ugh. that tastes like crap.
好了  手术室准备好了  你呢
Okay, the o.r.'s prepped and ready. how about you?
准备好了
Yeah, ready.
现在我尝到了粪便
Now i taste like crap.
当我们把"对不起"正确使用的话
When we get it right,
效果完美
"i'm sorry" is perfect.
为了伊兹  我们必须
Hey, so, um, we have to
把婚礼搁置一下
Move the wedding up for izzie.
她
She's...
好的
Okay.
你在整理你妈妈的日记
You're packing up your mom's journals.
是的
Yeah.
你知道吗  这里没有一篇是关于我的
You know, there's nothing in these for me.
我一直都想不明白
I keep thinking, but i don't know.
我不想把它们扔掉
I don't want to throw them away,
所以我想把它们送给主任
So i was gonna give 'em to the chief.
还有
And...
如果你想的话他可以参加我们的婚礼
He can come to the wedding if you want.
他可以参加
He can come.
好的
Okay.
当我们使用正确的时候  "对不起"能帮我们补救错误
When we get it right... "i'm sorry" is redemption.